Guide to the Harry Randall: Fifteenth International Brigade Films and Photographs ALBA.PHOTO.011
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series E: Miscellaneous, 1938-01-1939-09; 9594
  - Photo Unit #: E1451 15th International Brigade action shot, Sierra Pandols, Aug 1938; 9657 (Item 11-1715)
    (Moscow Number: 5/187/59)
  - Photo Unit #: E1452 MacKenzie-Papineau, Sierra Pandols, Aug 1938; 9656 (Item 11-1716)
  - Photo Unit #: E1455 MacKenzie-Papineau fortifying, Sierra Pandols, Aug 1938; 9655 (Item 11-1717)
    (Moscow Number: 5/187/49)
  - Photo Unit #: E1456 Soldier reading in trench, 304918 (Item 11-1879)
  - Photo Unit #: E1457 MacKenzie-Papineau fortifying, Sierra Pandols, Aug 1938; 9654 (Item 11-1718)
  - Photo Unit #: E1458 Henry Mack at Company 1, MacKenzie-Papineau Estado Mayor [Headquarters], Aug 1938; 9653 (Item 11-0111)
  - Photo Unit #: E1459 MacKenzie-Papineau, Aug 1938; 9652 (Item 11-0112)
  - Photo Unit #: E1460 Major Edward Cecil [?] Smith at phone, MacKenzie-Papineau Estado Mayor [Headquarters], Sierra Pandols, Aug 1938; 9651 (Item 11-1719)
  - Photo Unit #: E1461 Officers at MacKenzie-Papineau Estado Mayor [Headquarters], Sierra Pandols, Aug 1938; 9650 (Item 11-0113)
  - Photo Unit #: E1462 Frank Rogers and [?], MacKenzie-Papineau Commissars, Sierra Pandols, Aug 1938; 9649 (Item 11-1720)
  - Photo Unit #: E1463 Group of MacKenzie-Papineau, Sierra Pandols, Aug 1938; 9648 (Item 11-1721)
  - Photo Unit #: E1464 Matthew Mattison of MacKenzie-Papineau cutting tree down, Sierra Pandols, Aug 1938; 9647 (Item 11-1722)
  - Photo Unit #: E1465 MacKenzie-Papineau Battalion, Sierra Pandols [2 soldiers], Aug 1938; 9646 (Item 11-1723)
  - Photo Unit #: E1466 MacKenzie-Papineau, Sierra Pandols, undated; 9645 (Item 11-1724)
  - Photo Unit #: E1467 MacKenzie-Papineau, Sierra Pandols, Aug 1938; 9644 (Item 11-1725)
  - Photo Unit #: E1468 MacKenzie-Papineau, Sierra Pandols, Aug 1938; 9643 (Item 11-1726)
  - Photo Unit #: E1469 MacKenzie-Papineau firing trench mortar, Sierra Pandols, Aug 1938; 9642 (Item 11-1727)
  - Photo Unit #: E1470 MacKenzie-Papineau Battalion, rifleman, Sierra Pandols, Aug 1938; 9641 (Item 11-1728)
    (Moscow Number: 5/187/46)
  - Photo Unit #: E1471 MacKenzie-Papineau Battalion, fortifying, Sierra Pandols, Aug 1938; 9640 (Item 11-1729)
  - Photo Unit #: E1472 Fascist planes, Sierra Pandols [long view], Aug 1938; 9639 (Item 11-1730)
  - Photo Unit #: E1473 Bombing on horizon seen from Sierra Pandols [long view], Aug 1938; 9638 (Item 11-1731)
  - Photo Unit #: E1474 British Battalion, Sierra Pandols [2 soldiers, long view], Aug 1938; 9637 (Item 11-1732)
  - Photo Unit #: E1475 British Battalion, Sierra Pandols [2 soldiers, long view], Aug 1938; 9636 (Item 11-1733)
  - Photo Unit #: E1476 British Battalion, Sierra Pandols [2 soldiers, at stone wall], Aug 1938; 9635 (Item 11-1734)
  - Photo Unit #: E1477 British Battalion, Sierra Pandols [soldier, long view], Aug 1938; 9634 (Item 11-1735)
  - Photo Unit #: E1478 British Battalion, Sierra Pandols [landscape, long view], Aug 1938; 9633 (Item 11-1736)
  - Photo Unit #: E1479 British Battalion, Sierra Pandols [landscape, long view], Aug 1938; 9632 (Item 11-1737)
  - Photo Unit #: E1480 British Battalion Group, Company 2, Sierra Pandols [4 soldiers, close-up], Aug 1938; 9631 (Item 11-1738)
  - Photo Unit #: E1482 British Battalion, Jose Tecle, Sierra Pandols [rifleman], Aug 1938; 9630 (Item 11-1739)
  - Photo Unit #: E1483 British Battalion, armory, Sierra Pandols [3 soldiers with weapons and sandbags], Aug 1938; 9629 (Item 11-1740)
  - Photo Unit #: E1484 British Battalion, Estado Mayor [Headquarters], Sierra Pandols [group of soldiers sitting, one with bandaged head], Aug 1938; 9628 (Item 11-1741)
  - Photo Unit #: E1484 Estado Mayor [Headquarters], British Battalion, Sierra Pandols [group of soldiers sitting, one iwth bandaged head], Aug 1938; 9627 (Item 11-1802)
    (Moscow Number: 5/184/14)
  - Photo Unit #: E1485 British Battalion group, Sierra Pandols, Aug 1938; 9626 (Item 11-1742)
  - Photo Unit #: E1486 British Battalion, runners, etc. Plana Mayor, Sierra Pandols, Aug 1938; 9625 (Item 11-1743)
  - Photo Unit #: E1487 Fascists bombing Corbera, British Battalion, Sierra Pandols [long view], Aug 1938; 9624 (Item 11-1744)
  - Photo Unit #: E1488 Fascists bombing Corbera, Sierra Pandols; [smoke rising over hills], Aug 1938; 9623 (Item 11-1745)
  - Photo Unit #: E1489 Fascists bombing Corbera, Sierra Pandols [long view], Aug 1938; 9622 (Item 11-1746)
  - Photo Unit #: E1490 Fascists bombing Corbera, Sierra Pandols; [smoke rising over hills], Aug 1938; 9621 (Item 11-1747)
  - Photo Unit #: E1491 Lincoln-Washington group, Sierra Pandols, Aug 1938; 9620 (Item 11-1748)
  - Photo Unit #: E1492 Lincoln-Washington group, Company 3 [?], Sierra Pandols, Aug 1938; 9619 (Item 11-1749)
  - Photo Unit #: E1493 Grave of Joe Bianca, Lincoln-Washington, Aug 1938; 9618 (Item 11-0114)
  - Photo Unit #: E1494 Grave of Joe Bianca, Lincoln-Washington, Sierra Pandols, Aug 1938; 9617 (Item 11-1750)
  - Photo Unit #: E1495 Monument to fallen comrades and grave of Captain Egon Schmidt, Sierra Pandols, Aug 1938; 9616 (Item 11-1783)
    (Moscow Number: 5/181/21)
  - Photo Unit #: E1496 Monument to fallen comrades, Sierra Pandols, Aug 1938; 9615 (Item 11-1751)
  - Photo Unit #: E1497 Monument to fallen comrades, Sierra Pandols, Aug 1938; 9614 (Item 11-1752)
  - Photo Unit #: E1498 Monument to fallen comrades, Sierra Pandols, Aug 1938; 9613 (Item 11-1784)
    (Moscow Number: 5/181/22)
  - Photo Unit #: E1500 Harry Pollitt dining at Estado Mayor [Headquarters], Sep 1938; 9612 (Item 11-1757)
    (Moscow Number: 5/176/4)
  - Photo Unit #: E1504 Estado Mayor [Headquarters] at lunch, Corbera, Sep 1938; 9611 (Item 11-1212)
  - Photo Unit #: E1505 Battalion Commissars and Major José Antonio Valledor, Corbera, Sep 1938; 9610 (Item 11-1753)
  - Photo Unit #: E1509 Siesta (Commissariat), Corbera, Sep 1938; 9609 (Item 11-0567)
  - Photo Unit #: E1512 Company 4, Lincoln-Washington, Corbera, Sep 1938; 9608 (Item 11-0568)
  - Photo Unit #: E1517 [Training:] MacKenzie-Papineau Company 1 [or Lincoln Battalion?], digging fox holes, Sierra Pandols [3 soldiers], Sep 1938; 9607 (Item 11-1754)
    (Moscow Number: 5/187/35)
  - Photo Unit #: E1518 Company 1, MacKenzie-Papineau Battalion, Morris Colow, Thomas Lyons, Lieutenant Hans Kalbschmidt, Sep 1938; 9606 (Item 11-1846)
    (Moscow Number: 5/187/45)
  - Photo Unit #: E1519 MacKenzie-Papineau resting [in a grove], Corbera, Sep 1938; 9605 (Item 11-1296)
  - Photo Unit #: E1520 Lincoln-Washington group, Corbera, Sep 1938; 9604 (Item 11-0569)
  - Photo Unit #: E1533 Alvah Bessie and Ronald Bates, Corbera, Sep 1938; 9603 (Item 11-0570)
  - Photo Unit #: E1534 MacKenzie-Papineau olive grove, Corbera, Sep 1938; 9602 (Item 11-0571)
  - Photo Unit #: E1535 MacKenzie-Papineau group playing cards, Corbera, Sep 1938; 9601 (Item 11-0572)
  - Photo Unit #: E1536 Meeting of Battalion Commissars, Corbera, Sep 1938; 9600 (Item 11-0573)
  - Photo Unit #: E1538 Company 3, Lincoln-Washington (out of focus), Corbera, Sep 1938; 9599 (Item 11-0574)
  - Photo Unit #: E1539 Company 3, Corbera, Sep 1938; 9598 (Item 11-0575)
  - Photo Unit #: E1540 William N. Miller of Lincoln-Washington, and Harry Randall, Comisariado [Commissariat], Corbera, Sep 1938; 9597 (Item 11-0576)
  - Photo Unit #: E1541 Lincoln-Washington Sanidad [Health], Corbera, Sep 1938; 9596 (Item 11-0577)
  - Photo Unit #: E1542 Lincoln-Washington comrades watching planes, Sep 1938; 9595 (Item 11-0578)
- Series F. Films, circa 1937-1938; 501813
  Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
  Access copies for some films may be available by appointment for reading room viewing only. Please contact the Tamiment Library & Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives for more information and to schedule an appointment, tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.
  This series consists of three black-and-white 16 mm reels shot by Harry Randall during the Spanish Civil War. The films document the men and women who volunteered to participate in the conflict, either as members of the International Brigades or the affiliated medical services. The films capture a wide range of footage, including camp sites, military preparations, weather conditions, the landscape of the Spanish countryside, the administration of medical aid, and daily activities such as eating, bathing, sleeping, reading, and writing letters. The films also show the war's destruction, featuring numerous damaged buildings and structures.
  - Untitled Film Footage: Reel 1, 1937-1938; 501815; 1 Reels 16 mm; duration: 17:23 (Box 7, Reel 1, Dvd 1)
  - Untitled Film Footage: Reel 2, 1937-1938; 501816; 1 Reels 16 mm; Duration: 22:24 (Box 7, Reel 2, Dvd 2)
  - Untitled Film Footage: Reel 3, 1937-1938; 501817; 1 Reels 16 mm; Duration: 14:16 (Box 7, Reel 3, Dvd 3)
- Unprocessed Materials (Box 1, Box 2, Box 3, Box 4, Box 6, Box 5, Box 4A)